নে Translated from Spanish to English - www.onlinedoctranslator.com

DEVELOPERSOFT WARE

HTTPS://GITHUB. C OM / C AM I 9 8 7 3 5 2 6 4

CHRISTIAN CAMILO RODRIGUEZ **MONTEALEGRE**



CO NTA CTO **INFORMATION**

- mashlowtm0510@gmail.com
- +57-318-656-2061
- 🗎 June 5, 2006 Colombian
- linkedin.com/in/cristi%C3%A1 ncamilo-rodr%C3%ADquez-mont <u>ealegre-8a8697272/</u>

SKILLS

- ReactJS/NextJS, Frontend Development, UI/UX Practices
- Authentication/JWT, Google OAuth, Cookie Management
- Javascript (ES6+)
- MySQL/MongoDB and database administration
- NodeJS, Version Control / Git, NPM
- Communication assertive, thought critical
- Problem solving, analytical thinking, testing

LANGUAGES

• English (B2) | Intermediate level. British Council EnglishScore Certificate

Spanish | Native

PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE

Full Stack developer with a strong focus on the backend and one year of experience, with extensive knowledge in JavaScript, ReactJS and ExpressJS. Specialized in advanced programming, database management and UI/UX user experience. I have experience developing complex web platforms, artificial intelligence systems and API applications. I excel in solving complex problems and effective collaboration with multidisciplinary teams. As a self-taught person, I continually stay up to date with the latest technologies impacting the market, always seeking to improve my skills and knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PayBluem. | May 2024 - Currently

A sports platform developed in ReactJS and ExpressJS, which offers a comprehensive solution for the management of sports • Development of a full-stack platform with role management, routing

and authentication in ReactJS and ExpressJS to manage each phase of sports tournaments, using advanced and dynamic validations with the

team leaders to register and organizers to manage team participation.

- express-validator library. • Designed the registration and payment flow for tournaments, allowing
- Development of modules for the creation and management of group phases and direct phases, including the assignment of roles to referees and athletes associated with team leaders.
- Implementation of dynamic tournament bracket diagrams to visualize the phases and results of the matches.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PayBluem. | Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

License plate detection platform and software that uses the YoloV8 artificial intelligence algorithm for license plate recognition.

- Development of license plate recognition software using the YoloV8 artificial intelligence algorithm.
- Implementation of functionalities to study and map behavioral patterns based on the location of license plate records within the web platform hosted in static files using ExpressJS.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PayBluem. | Jul 2023 - Dec 2023

Colombian sign language interpretation platform that uses artificial intelligence with GPT-4 and the OpenAI API.

- Development of an API in ExpressJS to interpret Colombian sign language based on artificial intelligence using GPT-4 and the OpenAI
- Implementation of a system to translate natural language text into Colombian sign language, displayed by an interpreter on a green screen within a web platform built in NextJS.
- Development and optimization of algorithms for natural language processing and sign recognition to ensure accurate and fluid translation.

EDUCATION

PROFESSIONAL TECHNICIAN IN WEB PROGRAMMING

ITFIP (Tolimense Institute of Professional Technical Training).

San Isidoro Educational Institution. Espinal, Tolima,

Espinal, Tolima, Colombia | Feb 2023 - Currently BACCALAUREATE

PROJECTS

Sessions in Sensor System

Colombia | Feb 2022 - Dec 2022

In developing the sensor system, I created a comprehensive login and registration system using ExpressJS and email authentication. This included implementing functionality to send emails with dynamic login codes using temporary Google app credentials and the Nodemailer library. On the frontend, built with ReactJS and DaisyUI, these dynamic login codes were sent to users via email and seamlessly integrated into the login form, ensuring a smooth and secure authentication process.

Software for Graduates This software allows graduates to submit their education and jobs after

graduation so the university can track statistics. Developed the application views in ReactJS, including both the home page and the dashboard system. Designed the UI/UX using the DaisyUI component library to ensure visual consistency across the product. On the backend, using ExpressJS, I included secure authentication and session management systems. Additionally, I integrated an external public data API (universities in the country) to dynamically capture the user response from the inputs.

Vets System

Designed and developed the registration and login module, including creating the UI/UX of the application. I implemented a CRUD system to manage pet appointments, integrating dynamic data from the database such as the type of animal and the type of consultation (surgery, checkup, accident, etc.). The system was configured to include the prices of the consultations and display the relevant data on the screen. Advanced functionalities were integrated to improve the management and presentation of crucial information for veterinary practice.

WhatsApp Bot

I have implemented a GPT-4 based chatbot to answer various user questions, using advanced natural language processing capabilities to provide accurate and contextual responses. Additionally, I developed a WhatsApp bot using the whatsapp-web.js library, which allows image manipulation and sticker generation from normal and quoted messages, with custom meme generation capabilities.

RECOGNITION NT OSYAWARDS

• Recognition for achieving the highest score in the Higher Education Quality State Examination (ICFES) within the educational institution.

SAN ISIDORO EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION

- Notable distinction for academic excellence and outstanding
- performance on nationally standardized assessments.

REFERENCES

boss.

Jorge Leonardo Castro Arana, Founder of PayBluem, Colombia. Phone: (+57) 310 2777594. Email: jcastro60@itfip.edu.co . Relationship: Direct

Amanda Montealegre García, Head of social services and marketing division CAFASUR, Colombia. Phone: (+57) 311 8982038. Email:

amandamontealegregarcia@gmail.com . Relationship: Caregiving aunt.